American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IId. 1837-1844 APS.Archives.IId APS.Archives.IId
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Report of committee on E. Otis Kandall's paper on the longitude, November 15, 1839; American Philosophical Society.
    [as calculated] from the solar eclipse on September 18, 1838.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, November 15, 1839; 5" x 7 7/8"; Mease, James, 1771-1846
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S., in the name of Mr. Hugh Mercer, the Manuscript orderly book of General [George] Weedon from August, 1777, to May, 1778.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 18, 1839; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; DeWitt, Richard Varick
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Albany, l p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates to the A.P.S.: a plaster bust of Simeon DeWitt. See Pro., I, 150.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 19, 1839; 8" x 10"; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: Statutes-at -Large of South Carolina, V.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, Nov. 21, 1839; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: Per.P. Vaughan... Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1839; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William Ogilby. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 25, 1839; 9x7-1/2; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Hopkins. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 25, 1839; 10x8; Mercer, Hugh
    Fredericksburg, A.L.S. 2p.and add., end.,by James Mease James Mease has the Weedon papers and is to deposit them with the APS.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 26, 1839; 10x8; Royal Irish Academy
    Dublin Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jos.H. Singer. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 28, 1839; 7 1/4" x 9 1/8"; Lloyd, Humphrey, 1800-1881
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., Trinity College, Dublin, 2 pp. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letterto A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, December 1, 1839; 8 1/4" x 9 15/16"; Washington, John
    Secretary of the A.P.S., London, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 2, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Horner, William E. (William Edmonds), 1793-1853
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Recommends that skeleton of mastodon, offered for sale at $440, be purchased by American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 5, 1839; 5" x 8 1/8"; Poinsett, Mary
    Washington, 1p. A.L.S. Presents portrait of her husband [Joel R. Poinsett] to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Receipt to [David Bailie] Warden for payment for the American philosophical society, Dec. 6, 1839; 3x5-1/2; Institut de France
    Paris, Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and end. by [John vaughan]. In French. ----Duplicate. 5x8.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 6, 1839; 7 13/16" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp. and address. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter respecting trusteeship of his father's estate. Has received packet for A. P. S. from Prof. Lloyd. Has distributed almanacs.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 8, 1839; 10x8; Bridgman, E. C. (Elijah Coleman), 1801-1861
    Macao, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Enc. Concerning DuPonceau and Chinese writing. Encloses subscription paper for S.W.Williams A Chinese Chrestomathy.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache and John Vaughan, December 12, 1839; 8" x 10"; Mercer, Hugh
    Fredericksburg, 1 p., address and endorsement. Concerning donation of Valley Forge Orderly Book and General George Weedon's Letters to the A.P.S.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan, Dec. 17, 1839; 5-1/2x8; Eyriès, Alexandre
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Peter S.DuPonceau. 1p.and end.
  - Report of the committee of finance, Dec. 19, 1839; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Clement C. Biddle and George Ord. 1p. Copy.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Dec. 20, 1839; 9x7; Cunningham, George Godfrey
    Montreal, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards volume.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, December 21, 1839; 8" x 10"; Washington, John
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: [John] Davidson, Travels in Africa, and [D. H.] Kloff, Voyages through the Moluccan Archipelago.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, December 23, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a survey of East Prussia, in the name of [F. W.] Bessel. See Pro., I, 166.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 26, 1839; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Fisher, Joshua Francis, 1807-1873
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that his name be dropped from the list of candidates for secretaryship of American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 26, 1839; 9-3/4x8; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thaddeus M. Harris. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and asks for missing numbers.
  - Letter to John C. Clark, December 31, 1839; 5" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by John T. Durang. Receipted bill for $85.77, for designated journals.
  - List of catalogues of libraries in the library of the A[merican] P[hilosophical] S[ociety. Philadelphia], 1839; 7 7/8" x 13"; American Philosophical Society
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. D.
  - Report of [Peter Stephen Du Ponceau] on the Cochin-Chinese-Latin dictionary which is published, Jan. 3, 1840; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p. See Minutes of this date.
  - Report of the committee to which was referred... the donation of the orderly book of the American army at Valley Forge, January 3, 1840; 7 7/8" x 12 11/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[ohn] K. Kane, J[oshua] Francis Fisher, N[athaniel] Chapman. The orderly book of General George Weedon.
  - Letter to ----, January 8, 1840; 4 7/8" x 7 1/2"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    ----, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Calahan of the Texian boundary commission, who wishes to refer to the British Nautical Almanac for 1841 and Woodhouse's Trigonometry.
  - Letter to the Secretary of A.P.S., January 9, 1840; 7 3/8" x 9"; Hopkins, William, 1793-1866
    Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards last number of Transactions of Cambridge Philosophical Society. Wishes to obtain missing parts of A.P.S. Transactions, III.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Jan. 13, 1840; 10x8; Ingraham, Edward D. (Edward Duncan), 1793-1854
    A.L.S. 1p. Donates catalogues.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 15, 1840; 7 7/8" x 10"; Hollinshead, Benjamin M.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends to Mr. Vaughan, for the A.P.S.: an autograph letter of James Fenner, the tragedian.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 26, 1840; 5" x 7 1/4"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    University, [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to borrow Priestley's History of Electricity.
  - Statement of account of books for the American philosophical society's library to [David Bailie] Warden, Jan. 30, 1840; 5-1/2x7-1/2; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Paris, D.S.: Ledoren. 1p. In French.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 31, 1840; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Biblioteca nazionale (Naples, Italy)
    Naples, L. 1p.,end. Thanks for APS publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 1, 1840; 10-3/4x8-3/4; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, L.S.: Quetelet. 2p.and add. In French Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., February 7, 1840; 8" x 10"; Drayton, William, 1776-1846
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Withdraws from membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 17, 1840; 10x8; Ryan, Thomas D.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Expenses for forwarding society publications. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 17, 1840; 10x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Ogilby. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 18, 1840; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    70 Fenchurch St., [London], 2 pp. and address. L.S. Has sent 24 copies of A.P.S. Transactions, VI, pt. 3, to various persons and societies.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 21, 1840; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 24, 1840; 10x7-3/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, Feb. 25, 1840; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Washington. 1p.,end. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 27, 1840; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.and add.: Mr.P. Vaughan. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 28, 1840; 10x7-3/4; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, L.S.: Thaddeus M. Harris, Librarian. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 4, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Bowditch, N. I. (Nathaniel Ingersoll), 1805-1861
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of volume sent by A.P.S. Is considering publishing biography of his father.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 4, 1840; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Bowditch Library
    Boston, L.S.: H.I.Bowditch, and 3 others. 1p., end.and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 7, 1840; 9-3/4x8; London Institution
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Richd. Thomson. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 10, 1840; 9x7; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S: W.Hopkins. 1p.,end.and add.: Mr.Vaughan... Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 10, 1840; 9-3/4x8; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Forwards laws of S.Carolina.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 14, 1840; 12-3/4x8; British Museum
    L. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 15, 1840; 6 7/8" x 8 1/2"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Recommends the Baron de la Doucette for membership in the A.P.S.
  - Lease with the Athenaeum of Philadelphia, March 20, 1840; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 2p.and end. Copy. Attest: Wm. McIlhenney, Secy.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by Mr. [Isaac] Lea, March 20, 1840; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    on the Patella amaena of Say, Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S.: Philip H. Nicklin, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, Isaac Hays. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper... entitled "Observations of the magnetic intensity at twenty-one stations in Europe,", March 20, 1840; 7 7/8" x 10 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    by A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, [Philadelphia], 1 sp. and endorsement. D.S.: Joseph Henry, R[obert] M. Patterson, S[ears] C. Walker. Publicastions in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 20, 1840; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Librarian of A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Transactions, VI, pt. 3, which completes his set.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., April 2, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Hopkinson, Joseph, 1770-1842
    Philadelphia, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Deposits with the A.P.S.: original logbook of the Savannah, 1819, Captain Moses Rogers, "subject to order and disposal of the family."
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper entitled, April 3, 1840; 4 7/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    "On a new principle in regard to the power of fluids in motion... " by Charles Bonnycastle, ['Philadelphia],1 p. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, Rob[er]t Hare, Alexander] D[allas] Bache. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Report of the secretaries... upon the distribution of the Bulletin of the Societys Proceedings, April 3, 1840; 7 15/16" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S.: Franklin Bache, J[ohn] K. Kane, Robley Dunglison.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 6, 1840; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: F.Arago. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Peter S. Duponceau, April 10, 1840; 8 1/2" x 10 5/8"; Brown, John Porter, 1814-1872
    Constantinople, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has been endeavoring to make a perfect collection of Ottoman coins, which he now presents to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    A.P.S. Rooms, [Philadelphia] 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards to Mr. Vaughan a copy of the resolutions passed at the last meeting of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1840; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Ruffin, E. C.
    Petersburg, Va., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends two copies of Farmer's Register, VII, one to be given to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 10, 1840; 4 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 2 pp. A.L.S. Sends four sets of his Franklin to Mr. Vaughan, to be distributed as directed. FILM54-61 FRAME135
  - Report of the committee upon a paper entitled, April 17, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    "On the storm experienced... about the 20th. of October, 1836," by [Elias] Loomis, [Philadelphia], 1p. D.S.: A[lexander] D[allas] Bache. R[obert] M. Patterson. Report in favour of publication.
  - Letter to the Royal Netherland Institute, Amsterdam, April 17, 1840; 8-1/2x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S. 1p.and add. (from original in the Diederich Collection, Cu 3, University of Amsterdam Library.) Forwards APS publications for them and the societies at Haarlem and Rotterdam.
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, April 28, 1840; 8 1/16" x 9 15/16"; Rümker, Carl, 1788-1862
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Hamburg, 3pp., address endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S. Concerning three comets discovered at Berlin by Mr. Galle. FILM403 FRAME168
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 28, 1840; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Ogilby. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 30, 1840; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Audubon, Victor Gifford, 1809-1860
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Requests that account of $90 against A.P.S. be closed by payment thereof.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 30, 1840; 15x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William J. Hamilton, Sec. 1p.,end.and add.: Mr. P.Vaughan. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 30, 1840; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Royal Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    L.S.: W. A. Graham. 1p.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April, 1840; 10x7-1/2; Albany Institute
    Albany, A.L.S.: T. Romeyn Beck. 1p.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Dr. [Robert] Hare, May 1, 1840; 7 7/8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "Engraving and description of an apparatus and process for the rapid congelation of water," Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Franklin Bache, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, Ja[me]s C. Booth. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred Smith and Mason's paper upon nebulae, May 1, 1840; 7 5/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: Sears C. Walker, R[obert] M. Patterson. Publication recommended.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 1, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Copenhagen, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Is forwarding A[dolph Carl Peter] Callison's 28 vol. biographical and bibliographical study of authors of medical books in Europe.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, May 1, 1840; 10x8; Younge, Thomas F.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Expenses for forwarding society publication.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, May 2, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Callisen, Adolph Carl Peter, 1787-1866
    Copenhagen, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: an unnamed "literary work." The work was sold 5/44
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], May 2, 1840; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Forsyth. 1p. Forwards documents of the Congress to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 4, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864
    New Haven, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letter of January 28, and A.P.S. Transactions. Will forward all pamphlets requested by Mr. Vaughan.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 6, 1840; 10x7-3/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.and add.: Care of John Vaughan, end. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 6, 1840; 7 13/16" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 2 pp. and address. L.I. Has received parcel of reports from the Royal Society for A.P.S. Is glad Bank of U. S. will resume cash payments. Maine question not serious.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 8, 1840; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Thorndike, G. Herbert
    A.L.S. 1p. Presents records of Inquisition of Barcelona, preserved when the Casa de Inquisicion was destroyed in 1820 or 1821.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 10, 1840; 6 7/8" x 8 1/2"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has heard of Vaughan's indisposition, and hopes for his recovery. Acknowledges receipt of Philosophical Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 12, 1840; 8" x 10"; Jay, John C. (John Clarkson), 1808-1891
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of volumes [of A.P.S. Transactions?]. Still needs vol. I, o.s. Encloses check for $30 in payment for set.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 14, 1840; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Postpones communication to the A.P.S. Inquires as to status of Society's set of The Magazine of Natural History. FILM 235 FRAME 8
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 15, 1840; 8 3/8" x 10 3/8"; Dunlap, Thomas, ca. 1792-1864
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Presents specimens of crystals, found at the iron works of William Reed, to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 16, 1840; 7 3/16" x 8 7/8"; Carlisle, Nicholas, 1771-1847
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Society of Antiquaries of London donates Archaeologia, XXVIII.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 16, 1840; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846
    Oak Hill, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. offers to send specimens of stone from Indian workshop to A.P.S.
  - Statement to P[etty] Vaughan for cleaning and repairing the American philosophical society's telescope, May 20, 1840; 9x7-1/2 and 10x8; Dollond, George, 1774-1852
    London, D. 1p.and statement [1p.] by Petty Vaughan of expenses for the telescope.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 26, 1840; 10x7-3/4; Crabb, Wiiliam A.
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Will send all Pennsylvania geological reports.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 27, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Crabb, William A.
    Harrisburg, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends copy of Fourth Geological Report together with General Anthony's Report on the Nicholson land claims.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 27, 1840; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has forwarded a package of pamphlets, the impressions of Dixon's new discovery, and some books. Would like to know of their arrival.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, May 27, 1840; 8" x 9 3/4"; Tite, William, 1798-1873
    Librarian of the A.P.S., London, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Sends to the A.P.S.: second volume of the catalogue of the library of the London Institution.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 28, 1840; 8" x 12"; Desmond, Daniel J., d. 1849
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: copy of oration delivered at Georgetown College.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, June 3, 1840; 8" x 10"; Jay, John C. (John Clarkson), 1808-1891
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Inquires about five volumes of A. P. S. [Transactions?] which have not yet been received.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 4, 1840; 8 3/4" x 11"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Princeton, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Status of his set of Comptes rendus. Expects to come to Philadelphia on the 19th, "with budget of philosophical matter for the transactions." FILM 235 FRAME 9
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 4, 1840; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Webb, Thomas H. (Thomas Hopkins), 1801-1866
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has place two packages, entrusted to him by Mr. Vaughan, upon ship Dover, bound for Calcutta.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, June 5, 1840; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846
    Oak Hill, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has forwarded a box containing stones worked by the Indians, stone hammers, etc., to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 5, 1840; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Whittlesey, Elisha, 1783-1863
    Warren, Trumbull County, Ohio, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Sutliff, Who will present a copy of the Geological Survey of Ohio.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 8, 1840; Davis, John Philip, 1784-1862
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 12, 1840; 7 15/16" x 10"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Washington, 1 p. and address. Forwards "two copies of Mr. [John Quincy] Adam's report and one of the Oregon report."
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper entitled, June 19, 1840; 7 7/8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    "On the insufficiency of Taylor's theorem... " by Charles Bonnycastle, [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson, A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, S[ears] C. Walker. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred Mr. [Isaac] Lea's paper on the oalite formation in America, June 19, 1840; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsements. D.S.: Rich[ar]d C. Taylor, Ja[me]s C. Booth, Isaac Hays. Publication recommended.
  - An historical account of the origin and formation of the American philosophical society held at Philadelphia for promoting useful knowledge, June 19, 1840; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844